Finding Aid for Henry Hitt Crane Papers 1902-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Henry Hitt Crane Papers 1902-1977 1938-1964
Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977.
Methodist clergyman, pastor of the Centre Methodist Church in Malden, Massachusetts, the Elm Park Methodist Church in Scranton, Pennsylvania, and Central Methodist Church in Detroit, Michigan. Correspondence, 1938-1958, subject reference file, ca. 1902-1966, name reference file, 1938-1958, sermon file, 1925-1958, scrapbooks, 1928-1958, church bulletins and newsletters from church at which Crane pastored, sound tape recordings of messages preached by Crane, and visual materials consisting of photographs and motion picture film. The Crane papers document an interest in, and activities with, various liberal and progressive organizations, and his association and friendship with other clergy and individuals with similar pacifist and activist backgrounds.
85164 Aa 2
32.5 linear feet
1 motion picture film
1 optical disks DVDs
1 digital files streaming file
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Henry Hitt Crane (donor no. 4816 ) and came to the library in 1974. A second accession arrived in 1997 from Audrey Brodowicz (donor no. 8582 ).
The collection is open for research; the donor requests that the names of individuals receiving pastoral counseling not be cited.
The 16mm film in the collection was digitized in 2009 as part of a library video preservation project. A preservation master beta tape was created along with DVD and streaming file. The DVD is available for use in the library. The streaming files may be available online at a given time, but can be mounted on request.
Henry Hitt Crane was born in Danville, Illinois on February 2, 1890, the son of Charles A. Crane and Sallie Hitt Crane. In his boyhood he traveled as his father, a Methodist minister, was transferred about to different pastorates in Danville, Colorado Springs, and then Boston, where Charles Crane accepted appointment as pastor of the People's Temple. Coming from five generations of Methodist ministers, Henry Hitt Crane early on decided to follow in this family tradition. After graduating from Boston Latin School, he graduated from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut in 1913. Next came seminary work at the Boston University School of Theology, during which time in 1915 he married Helen Beck. He graduated from seminary in 1916 then followed this up with post-graduate work at Harvard.
Crane's first pastorate in Gorham, Maine was interrupted by the First World War. In 1917, he took a leave from his church to serve with the Y.M.C.A. in front line duty. His exposure here to the brutalities of war transformed Crane into a pacifist, a position to which he would adhere for the remainder of his life. Crane returned to Gorham for a brief period of time, then moved on to a Newton, Massachusetts church for two years from 1918 to 1920. For nine years (1920-1928), he was pastor of the Centre Methodist Church in Malden, Massachusetts. In 1928, he was appointed pastor of the Elm Park Methodist Church in Scranton, Pennsylvania. Located in the heart of the anthracite coal region, Elm Park was ranked as one of the three greatest Methodist Episcopal churches in the nation. Here Crane bolstered his reputation for controversy, organizing meetings of the American League Against War and Fascism, which the American Legion had labeled as "communistic." While at Elm Park, Crane took a year-long (1936-1937) sabbatical to tour the world to study for himself world conditions and the political tumult then occurring in Europe and the Far East.
In June 1938, Crane was appointed to the pastorate of the Central Methodist Church of Detroit. Central Methodist, located at the juncture of Woodward and Adams, had been built in 1866, and had a reputation of a "free and liberal pulpit." Crane was to flourish in this setting. He was both a gifted and prolific speaker, a writer of some note, and a champion of liberal causes. In the tradition of many nineteenth-century pastors, Crane used his pulpit to speak out on the issues of the day. Most especially, he espoused the cause of peace, supporting those who would be conscientious objectors during World War II and speaking out against the confrontational policies of the Cold War. He was a committed pacifist whose views during the 1950s and 1960s brought him much public attention and notoriety. Crane never backed down in his beliefs despite being listed as a suspected subversive by the House Un-American Activities Committee. Crane was also involved in other liberal causes. A staunch opponent of bigotry, Crane often spoke out against anti-Semitism and race discrimination. Through his efforts the Detroit Round Table of Catholics, Jews and Protestants was formed, a group that was influential in Detroit religious affairs.
Crane served at Central Methodist for twenty years before retiring in 1958. For the next nearly twenty years, Crane continued traveling and speaking throughout the country. He died May 19, 1977 at age 87.
The files of clergy are often narrow in scope encompassing only the activities of an individual within the setting of his/her own church. Henry Hitt Crane was more than the pastor of Central Methodist Church in Detroit. He was a nationally known speaker, eloquent in his advocacy of pacifism and civil rights. The Crane collection reflects the scope of his activities both within the churches he pastored, within the city of Detroit as an influential church leader, and nationally within larger Methodist circles and among other advocates of liberal causes similar to his own. Through his correspondence, articles, and published messages, we see Crane as representative of that class of nationally known clergymen, respected for their opinions, champion of progressive causes, and willing participants in the often contentious debates that followed World War I on matters of morality, politics, and social justice.
The Crane papers, with some exceptions, cover the period when Henry Hitt Crane first entered the ministry during the years of World War I and continuing past his retirement, until approximately 1964. There is decidedly less material from the years before his coming to Central Methodist Church in 1938; by far the largest bulk of documents date from 1938 to 1958 when Crane pastored this metropolitan church. The exceptions to the basic span dates of 1917 to 1958 are files collected by Crane of sermons, published pamphlets, and other materials of his father and uncle, also Methodist clergymen. There are also materials that date after 1958, mainly copies of messages received from other clergy with some correspondence.
The Crane papers have been maintained in the order as created by Crane and his secretarial staff at Central Methodist Church. The series in the collection are Correspondence, Subject Reference Files, Name Files, Sermon Files, Scrapbooks, Church Bulletins and Newsletters, Visual Materials, and Retirement Files.
Subjects:
American Civil Liberties Union.; American Friends Service Committee.; Clergy--United States.; Central Methodist Church (Detroit, Mich.); Centre Methodist Church (Malden, Mass.); Crane, Charles A.; Crane, Frank, 1861-1928.; Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977.; Democracy Unlimited (Organization); Detroit (Mich.)--Church history.; Detroit Round Table of Catholics, Jews, and Protestants.; Elm Park Methodist Church (Scranton, Pa.); Fellowship of Reconciliation (U.S.); Fellowship of Methodist Pacifists.; Methodist Episcopal Church--Michigan--Detroit.; Methodist Federation for Social Action (U.S.); Methodist preaching--Michigan.; Methodists--Michigan.; Pacifism.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953.; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953.; Stephan, Max Paul.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977.; Clergy.
Contributors:
Davis, Jerome, 1891-1979; Heard, Gerald, 1889-1971.; Littell, Franklin Hamlin.; Moffatt, James, 1870-1944.; Oxnam, G. Bromley (Garfield Bromley), 1891-1963.; Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1913-1969.; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Shelley, Rebecca, 1887-1984.; Smith, Lillian Eugenia, 1897-1966.
Genre/Form:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Sermons.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence, 1938-1958
  The series Correspondence, 1938-1958 (17.5 linear feet) has been arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Except for a few individual named files, this series consists of folders with alphabetical letter descriptions only (e.g., Fa-Far or We-Wj). For his twenty-year career at Central Methodist Church, Crane maintained a single alphabet for all of his voluminous correspondence. For the researcher interested in a specific name, this arrangement is ideal; for the researcher interested in a period of time, Crane's arrangement obviously poses difficulties. The series' great value is in showing the great breadth of Crane's correspondents. Part of the files are with members of his congregation, but of more significance perhaps are the letters exchanged with other Methodist clergy throughout the nation. In this latter category, the researcher will find discussions of current events, church politics, and the day-to-day challenges of being a member of the clergy.
  (Note: individual name files follow the mixed files for each letter)
  - A
    - Aa-Az (Box 1)
      multiple folders
    - Adkins, A. Carl (Box 1)
    - Adler, Norris (Box 1)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 1)
    - American Friends Service Committee (Box 1)
    - Arvad, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - B
    - Ba-Brox (Box 2)
    - Bru-Bz (Box 3)
    - Bellamy, Lois (Box 3)
    - Bishop, Corbett (Box 3)
    - Boston University (Box 3)
    - Bowles, Charles P. (Box 3)
    - Bowling Green University (Box 3)
    - Brown, Charles F. (Box 3)
    - Burr, Charles E. (Box 3)
  - C
    - Ca-Chi (Box 3)
    - Cho-Cuz (Box 4)
    - Case, Harold C. (Box 4)
    - Council of Churches (Box 4)
    - Crane, Henry H. (New Hampshire) (Box 4)
    - Crane, Henry H., 1948-1952 (Box 4)
    - Crane, Henry H., 1953-1955 (Box 5)
    - Crane, Henry H. (65th birthday party) (Box 5)
    - Crane, Henry H., 1956-October 1958 (Box 5)
  - D
    - Da-Do (Box 5)
    - Dr-Dz (Box 6)
    - Davis, Jerome (Promoting Enduring Peace) (Box 6)
    - DeFraine, Mr. and Mrs. Jack (Box 6)
    - Democracy Unlimited (formerly American Youth for Political Action) (Box 6)
  - E
    - Ea-Ez (Box 6)
    - Eddy, Sherwood (Box 6)
    - Eichel, Seymour and Julius (Box 6)
  - F
    - Fa-Fre (Box 6)
    - Fri-Fz (Box 7)
    - Fellowship of Methodist Pacifists (Box 7)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation (national) (Box 7)
    - Frost, Ralph W. (general secretary, Christian Associations) (Box 7)
  - G
    - Ga-Gz (Box 7)
    - Grant, Raymond (Box 7)
  - H
    - Ha-Hai (Box 7)
    - Hal-Hy (Box 8)
    - Harvard-Epworth Methodist Church (Box 9)
    - Harvey, M.S. (Box 9)
    - Haskell, Arthur (Box 9)
    - Heard, Gerald (Box 9)
    - Houser, Patty K. (Box 9)
  - I-J
    - Ia-Jy (Box 9)
    - Johnson, Warford B. (and family) (Box 9)
  - K
    - Ka-Kem (Box 9)
    - Ken-Kz (Box 10)
  - L
    - La-Ly (Box 10)
    - Lafayette College (Box 11)
    - Lewellen, Emery and Lena (Box 11)
    - Littell, Franklin (Box 11)
    - Littler, Mark (Box 11)
    - Luccock, Halford (Box 11)
    - Lyons, Wilson (Box 11)
  - M
    - Ma-Moo (Box 11)
    - Mor-My (Box 12)
    - McCobb, Jim and Martha (Box 12)
    - McLanahan, C.J. (Box 12)
    - Meacham, Stewart (Box 12)
    - Methodist Church (Box 12)
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action (Box 12)
    - Michigan (Box 12)
    - Milan Prison (Box 12)
    - Miller, Christine (Box 12)
    - Moffatt, James (Box 12)
  - N
    - Na-Ny (Box 12)
  - O
    - Oa-Oz (Box 13)
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1939-1958, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - P
    - Pa-Pz (Box 13)
    - Perrino, Tony and Mary (Box 13)
    - Phillips, John M, 1939-1945 (Box 13)
    - Phillips (John M.) family, 1945-1958, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Pierce, Eugene (Box 14)
    - Price, Bill and Helen, 1946-1958, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - R
    - Ra-Rz (Box 14)
    - Reisner, Ensworth, 1939-1958, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Reuther, Victor, Walter, and Roy (Box 14)
    - Rosenberg case, 1952-1954 (Box 14)
    - Round Table of Christians and Jews, 1939-1958 (Box 14)
  - S
    - Sa-Sch (Box 14)
    - Se-Sz (Box 15)
    - Safran, John (and family), 1943-1957, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Schaefer, J. Earl (Box 16)
    - Shelley, Rebecca (peace petition) (Box 16)
    - Smith, Lillian (Box 16)
    - Sojourner Truth Housing Project incident, 1942 (Box 16)
    - Staples, Lawrence (and family) (Box 16)
    - Starrett, Oscar and Adelia (Box 16)
    - Stein, J. Richard (Box 16)
    - Stephan (Max) case, 1943 (Box 16)
    - Stone, Ralph (Box 16)
    - Stone, Robert (Box 16)
    - Strike file (mainly automobile industry) (Box 16)
    - Swingle, Carmen (Box 16)
  - T
    - Ta-Tz (Box 16)
  - U
    - Ua-Uz (Box 16)
    - Uphaus, Willard (Box 16)
    - Utica (NY) Lenten Series (Council of Churches) (Box 16)
    - United World Federalists (Box 16)
  - V
    - Va-Vz (Box 16)
    - Vandercook, Del C., 1940-1958, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Van Deusen, Harry (Box 17)
  - W
    - Wa-Wz (Box 17)
    - Washington Pilgrimage (Box 18)
    - West Virginia Wesleyan University (Box 18)
  - Y-Z
    - Ya-Zz (Box 18)
    - Ziarko, Albert (Box 18)
- Subject Reference File circa 1902-1966
  Within the Subject Reference File, ca. 1902-1966 (1.75 linear feet), the researcher will find an assortment of materials mainly pertaining to Crane's interests and activities. Some of the files were probably originally created by Crane's father and uncle. These include, for example, the published essays of his uncle, Frank Crane, on different inspirational topics, and manuscripts of prayers probably authored by his father, Charles A. Crane.
  Crane used the Subject Reference File for his notes from his years of seminary study and for his senior thesis, "Socialism and the Kingdom of God." Here also are files relating to specific Methodist Church activities, notably his work with the Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1945-1952, and his involvement in a crusade against vice when he pastored in Scranton, Pennsylvania in 1934.
  - Atomic Age (Box 18)
  - Capitol punishment (Box 18)
    (pamphlet and letter to Charles Crane written by author Eben Bumstead)
  - Catholicism (Box 18)
  - Central Methodist Church (Detroit)
    - General background material, 2 folders (Box 18)
      (includes photograph-phonograph record combination)
    - Cooperative Discussion Group 1940s, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Durant (Will) message 1945 (Box 18)
    - Ushers (Box 18)
      notebook re ushers who served at Central from 1938 to 1958 include photos
  - Christmas messages sent out to congregation (Box 18)
  - Church and Economic Life (Federal Council of Churches) (Box 18)
  - Circuit riders (Box 18)
  - Contracts (Box 18)
  - Crane (Frank) published inspirational essays (Box 18)
  - Crane (Henry Hitt) biographical/personal
    - Doctoral thesis by Benjamin P. Mehrling entitled, "A rhetorical study of the preaching of Dr. Henry Hitt Crane" (Wayne State University, 1964) (Box 18)
    - Citation, etc. upon occasion of his leaving Elm Park Methodist Church in Scranton, PA. 1938 (Box 18)
  - Crane crest (Box 18)
  - Cuba (Box 18)
  - Death (Box 18)
  - Democracy (Box 18)
  - Democracy Unlimited (Box 18)
  - Detroit Round Table of Catholics, Jews and Protestants (Box 18)
  - Dictatorships (Box 18)
  - Dies Committee (Box 18)
  - Easter (Box 18)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Box 19)
  - Ethics course notes (Box 19)
  - Family (Box 19)
  - F.B.I. (Detroit) (Box 19)
  - Federal Union (Box 19)
  - Games (Box 19)
  - History research papers (Box 19)
  - Homiletics course notes (Box 19)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee (Box 19)
  - Institute on American Patriotism and World Peace 1940 (Box 19)
  - International Group (Box 19)
  - Japan (Box 19)
  - Jesus-Life and Teaching (Box 19)
  - Jews and anti-Semitism (Box 19)
  - Letters-Circular (Box 19)
  - Letters-Personal (Box 19)
  - Marriage prayer (Box 19)
  - McCarran immigration act (Box 19)
  - McCarthyism (Box 19)
  - Medicine (Box 19)
  - Memorial Day (Box 19)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action 1945-1952, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Michigan Housing Association (Box 19)
  - Mid-Century Conference on Peace (Box 19)
  - Militarism (Box 19)
  - Ministers No-War Committee (Box 19)
  - Ministry (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
  - Missions (Box 19)
  - Modern Community Developers (Box 19)
  - Motherhood (Box 19)
  - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 19)
  - National issues (Box 19)
  - North Atlantic Pact (Box 19)
  - Nuclear policy (Box 19)
  - Old Testament Theology course outline (Box 20)
  - Pageants and plays (Box 20)
  - Peacemakers bulletins (Box 20)
  - Pearl of Love (Box 20)
  - Pediatrics (Box 20)
  - Pension (Box 20)
  - Pentecost (Box 20)
  - Planned Parenthood (Box 20)
  - Poets
    (from class taken at Williams when HHC was 16 years old)
    - Bryant (Box 20)
    - Coleridge (Box 20)
    - Dante (Box 20)
    - Emerson (Box 20)
    - Holmes (Box 20)
    - Longfellow (Box 20)
    - Lowell (Box 20)
    - Shakespeare (Box 20)
    - Tennyson (Box 20)
    - Whittier (Box 20)
    - Wordsworth (Box 20)
  - Post War World Council, Detroit Chapter (Box 20)
  - Prayers (Box 20)
  - Preaching (Box 20)
  - Prohibition (Box 20)
  - Religious Freedom Committee (Box 20)
  - Religious Research (Box 20)
  - SANE nuclear policy (Box 20)
  - Science and religion (Box 20)
  - Scranton (Pa.) vice crusade 1934 (Box 20)
  - Smoking (Box 20)
  - Social Service course notes (Box 20)
  - Socialism and the Kingdom of God (Box 20)
    HHC senior thesis
  - Society of Good Neighbors (Box 20)
  - Spain (Box 20)
  - Thanksgiving (Box 20)
  - Tracts (Box 20)
  - Ushers Guild (Box 20)
  - Verse, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - War and the church (Box 20)
  - War Resister's League (Box 20)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 20)
  - Women's Society of Christian Service (Box 20)
  - World Neighbors, Inc. (Box 20)
- Name Reference File 1938-1958
  The Name Reference File, 1938-1958 (2 linear feet) contains a mixture of collected published materials pertaining to different religious and political figures together with some original correspondence. The researcher, because of the presence of such original material, should consult both this file and the Correspondence File for information or correspondence relating to specific individuals.
  - Ablett, Connie (Box 20)
  - Anonymous (Box 20)
  - Athearn, Walter Scott (Box 20)
  - Baldwin, Roger (Box 20)
  - Bellamy, Lois (Box 20)
  - Bishop, Corbett (Box 20)
  - Brown, Charles (Box 20)
  - Case, Harold C. (Box 20)
  - Chester, Alden (Box 21)
  - Choate, Joseph and Frances (Box 21)
  - Coughlin, Charles (Box 21)
  - Curtis, Mrs. Frank (Box 21)
  - Dancey, Thomas (Box 21)
  - Davis, Arthur (Box 21)
  - Devor, Richard (Box 21)
  - Dodd-Gara cases (Box 21)
  - Emrich, Richard (Box 21)
  - England, Frances (Box 21)
  - Enoch, Aden (Box 21)
  - Fischer, Louis (Box 21)
  - Flame of Youth (Box 21)
  - Foote, Gaston (Box 21)
  - Fosdick, Harry (Box 21)
  - Gower, Stanely (Box 21)
  - Grant, Ray (Box 21)
  - Griggs, Edward H. (Box 21)
  - Hallet, Mary (Box 21)
  - Haskell, Arthur (Box 21)
  - Heard, Gerald (Box 21)
  - Heller, Bernard (Box 21)
  - Hertz, R.C. (Box 21)
  - Hillary, Mark (Box 21)
  - Holdridge, H.C. (Box 21)
  - Hough, Lynn (Box 21)
  - Howard, Tryphena (Box 21)
  - Huber, Milton (Box 21)
  - Hughes, E.H. (Box 21)
  - Hustad, Hugo (Box 21)
  - Johnson, E. Shurley (Box 21)
  - Jones, David D. (Box 21)
  - Jones, Edgard DeWitt (Box 21)
  - Jones, E. Stanley (Box 21)
  - Jones, Jack (Box 21)
  - Jury, John R. (Box 21)
  - Kallen, H.M. (Box 21)
  - Kaynor, Pat (Box 21)
  - Kelly, Paul (Box 21)
  - Kennedy, Joe and Charlotte (Box 21)
  - Kingdon, Frank (Box 21)
  - Knox, Owen (Box 21)
  - Kraus, Arthur J. case (Box 21)
  - Laird, James (Box 21)
  - Lane, Patty (Box 21)
  - Lanz, Kay (Box 21)
  - Larson, Dave (Box 21)
  - Lawn edger (Box 21)
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 21)
  - Lindeman, Edward (Box 21)
  - Littel, Franklin (Box 21)
  - McConnell, F.J. (Box 21)
  - McLanahan, Jack (Box 22)
  - Martin, Everett Dean (Box 22)
  - Mayer, Milton (Box 22)
  - Meacham, Stewart (Box 22)
  - Michigan Housing Association (Box 22)
  - Millard, David D. (Box 22)
  - Miller, Marie (Box 22)
  - Moore, Max and Jean (Box 22)
  - Morris, Cedric (Box 22)
  - Muelder, Walter (Box 22)
  - Muste, A.J. (Box 22)
  - Mystery of Coincidence (Box 22)
  - Overstree, H.A. (Box 22)
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley (Box 22)
  - Phillips, John (Box 22)
  - Pino, John (Box 22)
  - Reuther, Walter (Box 22)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 22)
  - Rose, James (Box 22)
  - Rouillard, Irving (Box 22)
  - Safran, John (Box 22)
  - Schweitzer, Roy (Box 22)
  - Shedden, Dilys (Box 22)
  - Shelley, Rebecca (Box 22)
  - Simpson, Matthew (Box 22)
  - Slosson, Preston (Box 22)
  - Smith, Gerald L.K. (Box 22)
  - Smith, Lillian (Box 22)
  - Sorokin, Pitirim (Box 22)
  - Stephan, Max (Box 22)
  - Stidger, Bill (Box 22)
  - Uphaus, Willard (Box 22)
  - Vandercook, Del (Box 22)
  - Wade, R.J. (Box 22)
  - Warren, Luther (Box 22)
  - Wesley, John (Box 22)
  - Wheeler, Mabel (Box 22)
  - Wieman, Henry (Box 22)
  - Wieman, Regina (Box 22)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 22)
  - Young, Elizabeth (Box 22)
  - Young, George (Box 22)
- Sermon file, 1925-1958
  Sermon File, 1925-1958 (7.75 linear feet) consists of three subseries. One is an alphabetical sequence of typescripts and reprints of the sermons preached by Henry Hitt Crane while he was pastor of Central Methodist Church, 1938-1958. The second subseries is a card file with several sections. The most extensive is an alphabetical listing of sermon titles with the date(s) and place(s) where the message was given and followed by the notecards created by Crane in preparing the message. Unlike the subseries of sermon messages, this card file dates back to 1925. Smaller portions of the card file subseries document Crane's salary and speech honorarium payments. There is another card file, arranged alphabetically by city that lists the day, place, and title of message given by Crane. These card files, more than any other source, highlight the scope of Crane's speaking obligations. Crane in some years averaged more than one speech or sermon message per day. The third subseries within the Sermon File consists of reel-to-reel sound tapes of messages given by Crane at Central Methodist Church. There are approximately 150 reels in this series. Some of the tapes consist of messages given by other speakers. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., for one, spoke at Central Methodist in 1957.
  - Typescripts and reprints
    - Achieving the Impossible (Box 22)
    - Achieving an All-in Victory (Box 22)
    - Achieving the Resurrections (Box 22)
    - Adventure in Reunion (Box 22)
    - Altering the Angle of Attack (Box 22)
    - America is in the Heart (E. Shurley Johnson) (Box 22)
    - America of Our Desire (Box 22)
    - America of our Desires (Box 22)
    - Ancient Ark and Our Modern Dilemma (Box 22)
    - Anti-Semitism (Box 22)
    - Arcanium Arcanorum (Box 22)
    - Art of Character Building (Box 22)
    - Art of Communion (Box 22)
    - Art of Liking People (Box 22)
    - Art of Remembering (Box 22)
    - Art of Soul Growth (Box 22)
    - As If (Box 22)
    - As You Will (Box 22)
    - At Home to the Gods (Box 22)
    - Atomic Age Alternatives (Box 22)
    - Atonement (Box 22)
    - Authentic Americanism (Box 22)
    - Be Not Confounded (Box 22)
    - Be Ye Perfect-But How Can We? (Box 22)
    - Beds of Procrustes (Box 22)
    - Behold Your God (Box 22)
    - Belief and Conscience (Box 22)
    - Benefits Forgot (Box 22)
    - Blight of Boredom (Box 22)
    - Blind Spot (Box 22)
    - Bon Voyage (Box 22)
    - Brethren All (Box 22)